<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>International Herald Tribune</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.iht.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.iht.com</link>
	<description>The Best of Global Journalism</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 14:38:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Single-Tasking is the New Multitasking</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/single-tasking-is-the-new-multitasking/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/single-tasking-is-the-new-multitasking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 14:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Watch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=940</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Video Watch:  James Hamblin, one of the Atlantic&#8217;s editors explains how, trying to do too many internet things at once makes it hard to get anything done at all. Tabless Thursday is&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Video Watch: </strong> James Hamblin, one of the Atlantic&#8217;s editors explains how, trying to do too many internet things at once makes it hard to get anything done at all. Tabless Thursday is his idea of a vacation from distraction.<br />
<object id="flashObj" width="620" height="349" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"><param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="flashVars" value="videoId=3631149259001&#038;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theatlantic.com%2Fvideo%2Fiframe%2F373027%2F&#038;playerID=1065729157001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAABvb_NGE~,DMkZt2E6wO3dFlbHM7HTX1y1bVRDHLp_&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /><param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashVars="videoId=3631149259001&#038;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.theatlantic.com%2Fvideo%2Fiframe%2F373027%2F&#038;playerID=1065729157001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAABvb_NGE~,DMkZt2E6wO3dFlbHM7HTX1y1bVRDHLp_&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="620" height="349" seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" swLiveConnect="true" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash"></embed></object></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/single-tasking-is-the-new-multitasking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>France&#8217;s Homegrown Jihadists</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/frances-homegrown-jihadists/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/frances-homegrown-jihadists/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 14:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=937</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From the International New York Times-</strong> Stories of homegrown jihadists are becoming tragically familiar this year in France. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From the International New York Times-</strong></p>
<p>PARIS — When Dominique Bons speaks with her soft Toulouse accent, there is something tragic and dignified about this thin blond woman, recently retired from the military. Last December, she learned by text message of the death of her son Nicolas.</p>
<p>A French citizen who had converted to Islam, Nicolas Bons, 30, died as a suicide bomber, fighting for the jihadi cause near Homs, Syria. A few months earlier, his half brother, Jean-Daniel, 22, had also been killed in Syria. The two had traveled together to Syria from Toulouse.</p>
<p>Once there, they became poster boys for foreign jihad. They even posted a video on YouTube, calling on their “brothers” in France to join them.</p>
<p>Ms. Bons, herself an atheist, had watched helplessly as Nicolas changed his lifestyle, turning away from friends, drinking, dancing, dating. But when he sent a message from Syria, she was at a loss to understand.</p>
<p>“To convert to Islam, O.K., maybe this is not so serious,” she told the television channel France 2. “But Syria, that was a big shock.”</p>
<p>Stories of homegrown jihadists are becoming tragically familiar this year in France. A month after Nicolas’s death, also in Toulouse, two teenagers (whose names have not been released as they are minors), left one morning apparently to go to school; instead, they went to the airport and boarded a plane to Istanbul.</p>
<p>Once in Turkey, they called their parents to say they would be silent for a month, then flew closer to the Syrian border, which they crossed easily. The father of one of the boys, a Frenchman of Tunisian origin, also appeared on television, saying he was “shattered.” Like Ms. Bons, this middle-class father could not comprehend.</p>
<p>Eventually, the two grew disillusioned with the jihad, could not put up with the cold and left Syria. Back in France, they were charged with involvement in a “terrorist enterprise.”</p>
<p>Recruitment is still rising: An estimated 700 to 800 French citizens have gone to fight in Syria since the war started, with an increase of 75 percent in the last six months. According to the Interior Ministry, about 350 are currently fighting the Assad regime and at least 30 have been killed.</p>
<p>Foreign fighters in Syria come from all over Europe, but the French have provided the biggest group. French journalists held since last year in the infamous “factory of hostages” area near Aleppo, and released in April, were dismayed to discover that some of their hooded guards were, in fact, their countrymen.</p>
<p>This is not happening in faraway Waziristan. This new jihad is just on the other side of the Mediterranean. European Union citizens don’t even need a visa to go to Turkey, bordering Syria.</p>
<p>Who are these young men and, in some cases, women? What drives them? The days of Al Qaeda cells, of groups formed in radical mosques, easily monitored by police, are gone, experts say. This is the era of “lone wolves” — self-radicalized or radicalized in prison, brainwashed with videos of violence and martyrdom circulated on the Internet.<br />
Continue reading the main story Continue reading the main story</p>
<p>Recruiters, said Gilles Kepel, a professor at Sciences Po in Paris and an expert on political Islam, “have been very shrewd at using the language of social networks.” The GoPro camera, used to film attacks in real time, “provides the link between virtual and real.”</p>
<p>Mohammed Merah, 23 at the time, had a camera attached to his chest when he shot dead three French servicemen in Toulouse and nearby Montauban in March 2012. He also filmed his attack a few days later on a Toulouse Jewish school, where he killed three children and a teacher.</p>
<p>Many of the French jihadists come from the banlieues, the segregated suburban housing projects of big cities, but radical Islam also recruits among middle-class families. The French policy of strict secularism, which prohibits the burqa in public places and the Islamic head scarf in public schools, is a grievance used to attract female jihadists.</p>
<p>The French government, which has long relied on tough antiterrorist legislation, is tempted to take even harsher steps. It set up a toll-free phone line at the end of April to help concerned families, and in the first week alone, 24 cases of would-be jihadists, five of whom had already left for Syria, were uncovered. But the real shock came on May 30, when Mehdi Nemmouche was arrested in Marseilles, on a bus from Amsterdam, carrying a bag full of weapons and jihadist paraphernalia. Mr. Nemmouche, 29, has been held since then as the main suspect in the attack on the Jewish Museum in Brussels, which cost four lives on May 24.</p>
<p>Born in Roubaix, in what used to be the industrial heartland of France, to a broken French-Algerian family, he ran into trouble early and was jailed seven times in 10 years. The last sentence, five years for robbery, sealed his fate: Behind bars, he met radical Islamists and became one.</p>
<p>Three weeks after his release in December 2012, he went to Syria, where he fought for more than a year. Mr. Nemmouche’s jihad represents a step further: He is the first French fighter to come back from the Syrian battlefield to carry the jihad into the heart of Europe. With him, the dreaded threat has become reality.</p>
<p>Six months ago, Manuel Valls, then the interior minister, warned that jihadism is “the greatest danger we will have to face in the next few years.” Now, as prime minister, he is scrambling for new measures and European cooperation on the issue. But his fellow countrymen are still struggling to understand the deeper meaning of this menace in their midst.</p>
<p>(Sylvie Kauffmann is the editorial director and a former editor in chief of Le Monde) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/27/frances-homegrown-jihadists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Organizational Change Has Led to Chaos in Greenpeace</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/25/organizational-change-has-led-to-chaos-in-greenpeace/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/25/organizational-change-has-led-to-chaos-in-greenpeace/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 11:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From Der Spiegel Magazine-</strong> Last week, news emerged that a Greenpeace employee had lost millions in donor money through ill-conceived currency deals. Now the environmentalists are in danger of losing their biggest asset: their credibility.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From Der Spiegel Magazine-</strong> Last week, news emerged that a Greenpeace employee had lost millions in donor money through ill-conceived currency deals. Now the environmentalists are in danger of losing their biggest asset: their credibility.</p>
<p>On the day the scandal hit newspaper headlines, Greenpeace International Executive Director Kumi Naidoo didn&#8217;t panic. A South African with Indian roots who grew up in a township under the apartheid regime, a couple million missing euros was far from the worst Naidoo had seen.</p>
<p>Instead of tearing out his hair, Naidoo twittered cheerfully about a lecture he was giving on the dispersal of power. He wished other climate activists happy birthday and counseled &#8220;young people out there&#8221; not to &#8220;put any faith in the current generation of adult leaders.&#8221;</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Naidoo hasn&#8217;t been particularly committed to following his own advice. Had he been, the organization he leads, Greenpeace International (GPI), might not have found itself facing a crisis last Monday after having lost 3.8 million ($5.2 million) through currency trading.</p>
<p>Acting independently and in violation of the organization&#8217;s regulations, a finance department employee signed forward currency contracts worth 59 million to minimize Greenpeace&#8217;s currency risks. But when some of the contracts came due, the European currency had &#8212; contrary to expectations &#8212; risen against many others.</p>
<p>The damage extends far beyond the lost millions. Greenpeace has been careful to cultivate an image as intrepid defenders of the environment. Calling themselves the rainbow warriors, activists hang from factory chimneys, throw themselves in front of whaling ships or risk jail time in Russia by calling attention to the plight of the Arctic. Now, another activity has been added: playing the financial markets. For an organization almost entirely financed by donations, the revelation is a PR disaster, endangering from one day to the next the greatest asset Greenpeace possesses: its credibility.</p>
<p><strong>Greenpeace&#8217;s New Direction<br />
</strong><br />
This scandal is about much more than one person&#8217;s momentous mistake, it&#8217;s about an entire organization in a state of upheaval. Naidoo wants to shift Greenpeace&#8217;s focus from the industrialized countries to Africa and countries like Brazil, China and India. That, he argues, is the only way to counteract the threat of climate change. &#8220;We need to create an understanding in the developing countries that we will lose our planet if they follow the example of the industrialized nations,&#8221; Naidoo says.</p>
<p>Since he took the job in 2009, Naidoo has put all of the organization&#8217;s efforts into raising sustainability-awareness in the world&#8217;s emerging economies. It&#8217;s a huge effort that is plunging Greenpeace into disorder. It&#8217;s also expensive: In 2012, Greenpeace spent close to 90 million on fundraising &#8212; one third of all expenditures. And that&#8217;s not the only thing angering critics. Naidoo also envisions future campaigns no longer being coordinated from Amsterdam, but delegated to various national offices, requiring more coordination and communication. Just integrating the different cultures involved in the organization requires so much effort that other things have been neglected, like financial oversight.</p>
<p>If GPI was still the tightly run organization it once was, the risky investment strategy would never have come to pass, or at the very least, a professional crisis management apparatus would have been on hand to deal with it. Instead, Naidoo rushed to Boston to receive a prize for his civil disobedience-related pursuits.</p>
<p>When Naidoo returned to Amsterdam on Thursday, Greenpeace Germany, the branch that attracts the most donations, had lost 700 supporting members. Greenpeace Switzerland, which is just as financially robust, wrote a dismayed letter to its supporters asking &#8220;for forgiveness, from the bottom of their hearts.&#8221;</p>
<p>But while the national bureaus were placating enraged donors, top staff members were meeting in Arnheim to discuss staffing issues, leaving many of the desks at Greenpeace headquarters empty. At least one staffing issue has been cleared up though: The finance-department employee who finalized the contracts was fired.</p>
<p><strong>Vacuum Led to Mistake</strong></p>
<p>The lack of supervision is a direct result of Greenpeace&#8217;s restructuring. Because the campaigns have been delegated to individual countries, Greenpeace headquarters has become less important. Kumi Naidoo is rarely present and doesn&#8217;t even have his own office there. He confirmed that many of the 150 people who work at headquarters will have to go; the main office is dissolving.</p>
<p>When former Chief Operating Officer Willem van Rijn left the organization  in December 2012, his successor didn&#8217;t arrive until May 2013. It was during this leaderless time that a finance department employee had the grandiose idea to sign massive and unsupported forward contracts with the currency broker Monex Europe. The euro crisis hadn&#8217;t yet ended and the Greenpeace employee was certain that the value of the euro would drop.</p>
<p>Because Greenpeace International regularly sends large sums of money to fund national bureaus that cannot finance themselves, he bought 14 different currencies last spring, including Russian rubles, Chinese yuan and Thai baht.</p>
<p>Deals to limit exposure to the vagaries of the currency markets are normal in international business. Most, though, are limited to a span of just a few months to maintain flexibility. But the Greenpeace employee signed longer-term contracts. He bought currencies worth 36 million in 2013, and an additional 23 million in 2014. And the euro went up.</p>
<p>Greenpeace International management didn&#8217;t notice that they were sitting on a time bomb until August 2013. Lawyers were brought in, but the contracts were watertight. There was no escape.</p>
<p><strong>Imposed Silence</strong></p>
<p>Then came Greenpeace&#8217;s second mistake: It said nothing. Greenpeace Germany wasn&#8217;t informed of the situation until March 2014, after the losses had already been recorded on the balance sheet. Many other bureaus didn&#8217;t find out until a May meeting in Madrid. Even then, though, the story didn&#8217;t get out. It only hit the headlines last week.</p>
<p>The organization has explained its cover-up by saying it was waiting for the final audit by KPMG, the business consulting firm it had hired. They say they would have naturally included the losses in the soon-to-be published 2013 annual report, including the 2.1 million losses forecast for 2014.</p>
<p>But did management hope to the issue would somehow go unnoticed? Perhaps Naidoo underestimated just how explosive the news would be. The South African has a different style than his two German predecessors, Thilo Bode and Gerd Leipold. The minutiae of daily business are not his thing &#8212; a political scientist who completed his PhD at Oxford, Naidoo sees himself less as a manager and more as climate-change ambassador.</p>
<p>The tall, charismatic executive director is constantly jetting around the world, from the World Economic Forum to the Munich Security Conference, to save the world and convince companies, unions and religious leaders to take part in the fight against climate change. There&#8217;s hardly any time left in his 70-hour workweek to check the balance sheets.</p>
<p>As an adolescent, Naidoo got his start by fighting against the apartheid regime in his hometown of Durban. He was exiled and then worked for Nelson Mandela&#8217;s ANC after the latter&#8217;s release from prison. He led Civicus, a civil-rights organization, until 2008.</p>
<p>In Naidoo, Greenpeace found a man who, instead of being a dyed-in-the-wool environmentalist, combined environmentalism with social issues. His role models are Mandela and Gandhi. He wants cooperation instead of singular triumphs. When it comes to environmentalism, he argues, everybody should be willing to talk to everybody.</p>
<p><strong>&#8216;It Can Never Happen Again&#8217;</strong></p>
<p>The Germans in particular pushed back against his leadership style, afraid of losing their clout at home. There have also plenty of disagreements centering on money, focusing on questions as to how much the German chapter must provide to others and whether donors should be informed about the new focus? There wasn&#8217;t even an informational campaign regarding Greenpeace&#8217;s new direction.</p>
<p>German Chief Executive Officer Brigitte Behrens plays down the conflict. So far, she says, the delegation of international campaigns has worked and supporters are regularly informed about all activities through Greenpeace news. She also argues that German donations haven&#8217;t been affected by the misbegotten purchase of foreign currencies. Because of Greenpeace Germany&#8217;s organizational structure and strict legal restrictions in the country, the donations can only be used for campaigns. But, even so, the money is gone. &#8220;I&#8217;m very shaken,&#8221; she says. &#8220;It can never be allowed to happen again.&#8221;</p>
<p>Naidoo will try to compensate for the loss by saving on infrastructure, and not by cutting back on campaigns. The supervision gap has been closed, he says. From now on, all foreign currency contracts must have leadership&#8217;s blessing.</p>
<p>But the PR damage remains. &#8220;We will overcome this scandal,&#8221; GPI program director and Greenpeace veteran Pascal Husting believes. &#8220;But I was always proud that Greenpeace had a clean slate. This thing is going to stick to us forever.&#8221;</p>
<p>(Translated from the German by Thomas Rogers) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/25/organizational-change-has-led-to-chaos-in-greenpeace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why We Are Posting Secret Documents</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/why-we-are-posting-secret-documents/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/why-we-are-posting-secret-documents/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 10:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=927</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From Der Spiegel- </strong>Documents leaked by Edward Snowden show that Germany is home to the NSA's most important activities on the Continent. It's time the German public knew what they are -- and about their own government's involvement.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From Der Spiegel- </strong>Documents leaked by Edward Snowden show that Germany is home to the NSA&#8217;s most important activities on the Continent. It&#8217;s time the German public knew what they are &#8212; and about their own government&#8217;s involvement.</p>
<p>In the wake of the NSA scandal, the relationship between Germany and the United States has been rocky. When the first Snowden leaks emerged last summer, Chancellor Angela Merkel&#8217;s government declared the affair over before it even got going. But when Berlin learned last autumn that Merkel&#8217;s private cell phone had been monitored, the trans-Atlantic relationship hit a new low. There were discussions of possible consequences and of changes being necessary in the way Germany approached its North American ally.</p>
<p>Then the chancellor travelled to Washington and peace returned. Ever since, trans-Atlantic policy-makers and intelligence agencies have been yearning to return to normalcy, to a world in which the division of labor is clear: the NSA as omnipotent global intelligence service, and the Germans as their willing helpers. In the pre-Edward Snowden era, this division of labor was wrong. Now, it is downright negligent.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL has now released dozens of crucial documents that show how the NSA operates in Germany and how tightly it works together with the Bundesnachrichtendienst (BND), Germany&#8217;s foreign intelligence agency. The material in Snowden&#8217;s cache shows that Germany is the NSA&#8217;s most important location in continental Europe.</p>
<p>In the German capital, antennae installed on the roof of the US Embassy can listen in on Berlin&#8217;s government district. In the NSA&#8217;s European headquarters in Griesheim, located in the central German state of Hesse, the Americans sift through emails and phone conversations from Europe and Africa in order to extract usable information. US interests are, after all, diverse and broad &#8212; ranging from the Islamists in Yemen to the German chancellor in Berlin.</p>
<p>The NSA isn&#8217;t merely an intelligence agency, it&#8217;s a power-political instrument that safeguards &#8220;information dominance for America,&#8221; as one-time NSA head Kenneth Minihan once put it. It isn&#8217;t just aimed at terrorists or heads of government, but at German citizens: Their emails and text messages also run through the intelligence agency&#8217;s computers.</p>
<p>Partners and Adversaries</p>
<p>The German government has long tolerated US arrogance </p>
<p>Berlin suspected some of what was going on and chose to ignore much more. But it also had concrete knowledge about the omnipresence of the NSA, primarily because the BND played a role in its operations. The fact that the BND cooperates intensively with the NSA &#8212; and not just when it comes to counter-terrorism, but also in the undifferentiated mass monitoring of global communications &#8212; is demonstrated by documents from the Snowden archive. The Germans are partners and adversaries at the same time.</p>
<p>The chancellor swore an oath to defend the German constitution. Furthermore, spying on Germany is not allowed according to the criminal code. The constitutional rights of German citizens are not bendable according to the current state of German-American relations.</p>
<p>There are two possible explanations for what happened. The first is that the US and German governments coordinated with one another to determine what the NSA is allowed to do in its facilities in Griesheim, Wiesbaden, Berlin, Frankfurt and Stuttgart. If that&#8217;s the case, the chancellor and her interior minister need to inform the public, because it means they share blame for the actions of the Americans &#8212; and for the Americans&#8217; apparent use of data acquired in Germany to kill suspected terrorists.</p>
<p>The second possibility is that the NSA is acting on German soil without the knowledge and approval of the German government. If that&#8217;s the case, their operations constitute espionage and should prompt the German government to act as it does in other, similar cases.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL&#8217;s publication of the secret documents is also in the interests of the German government. Berlin has attempted to convince Washington to hand over the NSA&#8217;s Germany files &#8212; without success. It is thus hardly surprising that intelligence agencies and parliamentarians have asked SPIEGEL for access to the Snowden documents. Journalists are, first and foremost, tasked with informing the public, which rightly expects that it will be told what the NSA is doing and what it is allowed to do.</p>
<p>The partnership between the United States and Germany would improve were it freed of its emotional baggage. Some of the two countries&#8217; interests coincide. But others do not. When in doubt, the German government should side with those being spied on, and not with those doing the spying.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/why-we-are-posting-secret-documents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t be Fooled By Marine Le Pen</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/dont-be-fooled-by-marine-le-pen/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/dont-be-fooled-by-marine-le-pen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 10:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From Prospect Magazine-</strong> In 2002, French Journalist Christine Ockrent had the dubious honor of moderating Marine Le Pen's first TV performance, here, she explains why Marine Le Pen sells. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From Prospect Magazine-</strong> It took Jean-Marie Le Pen 42 years to build his political movement on the ruins of “French Algeria” and the remnants of pre-World War II fascist ideology. It has taken his daughter just over three years to transform the National Front into a party palatable enough to take the lead in the latest European elections.</p>
<p>Marine, 45, is blue-eyed, blonde, stout, aggressive and talented. A lawyer with a smoker’s voice, she has been in politics since she was 18. Enthused with her father’s oratory, her whole life ensconced in the family estate near Paris after two divorces, she has been smart enough to dissociate herself from her father’s anti-Semitic obsessions. She openly contradicted him for the first time in June over a comment he made about a Jewish pop star in which he appeared to refer to the Holocaust. The dyed-in-the-wool old activists may have thought she was too soft at first, but she has delivered victory.<br />
<strong>From Prospect Magazine-</strong> The National Front today has just one face: a woman &#8211; the only female leader in French politics &#8211; whose looks, personal history and lifestyle seem commonplace enough to appeal to a wide variety of voters. Women see no condescending attitude; those on low incomes, deserting the left, like her vocabulary; the young, bored with mainstream political egos and tricks, find her provocative; successful second generation immigrants, who want law, order and fewer foreigners, agree with her arguments.</p>
<p>The far-right today is an aggregate of several layers: anti-Semitic, anti-Muslim, anti-immigration, anti-globalization, anti-liberal “Anglo-Saxon” market economy and, finally, anti-Europe. The pyramid is all wrapped up in “Bleu Marine” &#8211; the slogan she has chosen to forge her brand.</p>
<p>In 1984, when Jean-Marie Le Pen appeared for the first time on the main political TV show of the day, “L’Heure de Vérité,” it was a national scandal. The rumor was that François Mitterrand, then president, had encouraged it in his successful ploy to weaken Jacques Chirac’s conservative party before the European elections &#8211; Le Pen got just under 11 percent of the vote. Marine was on the set, watching her father.</p>
<p>In 2002, I had the dubious honor of moderating her first TV performance, when we needed to balance comments about the political earthquake of the time: her father’s ousting of Lionel Jospin, the Socialist Party candidate and outgoing prime minister, from the presidential contest. A welcome change to her father’s contemptuous and hysterical manner with journalists, she was impressive, self-assured and already able to assert the most blatant lies and fallacies with inbred aplomb. Now, 12 years later, just watch her on stage: She loves it. She relishes the lights, the stardom and the fight. She thrives at knocking her opponents down, all clenched words and fists, then smiling at her admirers with self-satisfaction.</p>
<p>Marine works hard. She has ousted her father’s inner circle, picked up her own praetorian guard, who owe her their seats and sometimes more &#8211; her current companion, Louis Alliot, is vice president of the party.</p>
<p>She also understands that French politics trusts expertise gained in the traditional, elite education system. Her most influential adviser, Florian Philippot, has degrees from the École Nationale d’Administration, which trains senior French officials, and HEC, a prestigious business school.</p>
<p>Her vocabulary has switched marketing tactics: Marine talks patriotism rather than nationalism, the love of France rather than the fear of foreigners and she disputes the term “extrême droite.” She has so successfully laundered the image and the core rhetoric of the National Front that the mainstream media have adjusted as well. No more soul-searching about the diabolical dimension of the far-right, or the moral implications of interviewing its representatives. On European election night, most journalists talked about it as “the first political force in the country” &#8211; a factual mistake given the majority of absentees, but also the baseline of the posters the National Front had already printed before the official results came in.</p>
<p>Marine Le Pen sells. Radio and TV want her. Magazines put her winning smile on the cover, making the story of the National Front less political and more human interest. But it might not last. For all the “Bleu Marine” rebranding, the National Front remains true to itself.</p>
<p>(Christine Ockrent is a former editor of L&#8217;Express.) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/19/dont-be-fooled-by-marine-le-pen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Syria will Become Another Somalia</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/syria-will-become-another-somalia/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/syria-will-become-another-somalia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 15:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=918</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From Der Spiegel Magazine- </strong>For almost two years, Lakhdar Brahimi sought to bring peace to Syria. But in May, the United Nations special envoy stepped down. He speaks with SPIEGEL about Syria's situation. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From Der Spiegel Magazine- </strong>For almost two years, Lakhdar Brahimi sought to bring peace to Syria. But in May, the United Nations special envoy stepped down. He speaks with SPIEGEL about the stubbornness of Syrian President Assad, the mistakes of the West and the dangers presented by Islamic radicals.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Mr. Brahimi, in May, you stepped down as the United Nations special envoy to Syria. When you took the position in 2012, many considered the task of achieving peace in Syria to be a mission impossible. What did you hope to achieve?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The idea was, and still is, for Bashar al-Assad to agree to become the kingmaker instead of staying on as president, an orderly transition with his participation to go to the new Syria. This is what I was and still am dreaming of.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Can you point to a particular incident that showed you that it was time to give up?</p>
<p>Brahimi: When I ended the second round of discussions at the so-called Geneva II conference at the beginning of this year, I realized that this process was not going to move forward any time soon.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What happened?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Neither Russia nor the US could convince their friends to participate in the negotiations with serious intent.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: To what degree is the dispute about the person of President Bashar al Assad?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The issue of President Assad was a huge hurdle. The Syrian regime only came to Geneva to please the Russians, thinking that they were winning militarily. I told them &#8220;I&#8217;m sure that your instructions were: &#8216;Go to Geneva. But not only don&#8217;t make any concessions, don&#8217;t discuss anything seriously.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What about on the other side?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The majority among the opposition were against coming to Geneva. They preferred a military solution and they came completely unprepared. But at least they were willing to start talking with President Assad still there as long as it was clear that, somewhere along the line, he would go.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: So, you didn&#8217;t have a chance at all?</p>
<p>Brahimi: I told the Americans and the Russians several times while we were preparing for Geneva that they were bringing these two delegations kicking and screaming, against their will.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: For the sake of his country, why couldn&#8217;t President Bashar accept a replacement leader that everybody could live with?</p>
<p>Brahimi: It is his regime. He still has an appetite for power. The regime is built around his person and he still has enough authority over people that having him stay in power is a fundamental part of their vision of the future. The way he puts it is, &#8220;The people want me there and I cannot say no.&#8221; He said, &#8220;I am a Syrian national. If I have 50 percent plus one vote at the elections, I&#8217;ll stay. If I have 50 percent less one vote, I will go.&#8221; Yesterday he was just re-elected for another seven years! You have a situation where one side says there can be no solution unless Assad stays in power. While the other side says there can be no solution unless Assad goes. Do you know how to square a circle?</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Is Assad aware of the way the war is being conducted by his army?</p>
<p>Brahimi: One-hundred percent.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: The barrel bombs being thrown from helicopters on civilian populations? The targeted bombing of hospitals? The systematic torture and killing of thousands or tens-of-thousands?</p>
<p>Brahimi: He knows a hell of a lot. Maybe he doesn&#8217;t know every single detail of what is happening, but I&#8217;m sure he is aware that people are being tortured, that people are being killed, that bombs are being thrown, that cities are being destroyed. He cannot ignore the fact that there are 2.5 million refugees. That number is going to be 4 million next year, and there are 6 million people who are internally displaced. He knows that there are 50,000 to 100,000 people in his jails. And that some of them are tortured every day.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Did you confront him with those facts?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Sure! I spoke to him of a list of 29,000 people in his prisons and I gave a copy of the list to his office.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Is the regime the major culprit or are war crimes also committed by others?</p>
<p>Brahimi: War crimes are being committed every day, by both sides. Starvation is being used as a weapon. When you prevent water and food from reaching 250,000 people, what else can you call that? And at the same time, some of the armed groups are using civilians as human shields. But the regime has a state, has an army with 300,000 men, has airplanes, which the opposition doesn&#8217;t have.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Does anybody track those war crimes and hold people responsible?</p>
<p>Brahimi: There is an investigation commission, working under the umbrella of the High Commission of Human Rights, that has been trying to look at all these human rights abuses and they are systematically collecting facts. People will be held responsible one day.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Who is the dominating force in the armed opposition?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The opposition is very fragmented, even the Free Syrian Army. But everybody understands that the jihadi group ISIS (Eds. Note: The Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant) is not really interested in Syria. They seek to establish a new order in the region. As long as there are no negotiations, the armed groups as well as the political opposition will continue to be fragmented.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Are any of those groups capable of winning the fight against Assad and his regime?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The United Nations secretary general has been saying all along that there is no military solution. Neither the regime, nor the opposition can win a decisive military victory.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What is your prediction for the future of Syria and the region?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Unless there is a real, sustained effort to work out a political solution, there is a serious risk that the entire region will blow up. The conflict is not going to stay inside Syria. It will spill over into the region. It&#8217;s already destabilizing Lebanon, there are 1.5 million refugees in the country; that represents one third of the population. If it were Germany, it would be the equivalent of 20 million. It is destabilizing because ISIS </p>
<p>SPIEGEL:  the most radical and brutal armed opposition group, which seeks to establish a militant Islamic state </p>
<p>Brahimi:  is active in both Syria and Iraq already, and Jordan is really struggling to continue resisting. Even Turkey! According to a senior Iraqi official, ISIS has carried out 100 operations in Syria and 1,000 operations in Iraq in just three months.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: How could these radical forces emerge so quickly? Sources say that the Syrian regime itself helped unleash this phenomenon deliberately &#8212; that they have released hundreds of extremists from their prisons, even encouraging them to create an enemy that they can legitimately fight against. Is this correct?</p>
<p>Brahimi: I have heard this several times. People will tell you that ISIS controls one province and the government never attacks them. It is probably the government&#8217;s way of saying: &#8220;This is the future you will have if we are not there anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Will the states of Jordan, Iraq, Lebanon and Syria be able to survive?</p>
<p>Brahimi: They will not completely disappear as states, but it reminds me a lot of 1999. Then, I resigned from my first assignment as UN special envoy to Afghanistan because the UN Security Council had no interest in Afghanistan, a small country, poor, far away. I said one day it&#8217;s going to blow up in your faces. It did.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What is the link to Syria?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Syria is so much worse! This ISIS, they don&#8217;t believe in just staying there. And they are training people. Your countries are terribly scared that the few Europeans that are there may come back and create all sorts of problems. So just imagine what the feelings are next door!</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Did the West make significant mistakes when the conflict broke out?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Most people did, the product of a wrong reading of the situation inside Syria &#8212; just as events in Tunisia and even in Libya were misread by most people.<br />
 People have got it wrong every time. Which is understandable. It is complicated and these events erupted on us when we weren&#8217;t looking. What is difficult to understand is that the early, mistaken assumptions have not been revised. On all sides, people still help the war effort instead of the peace effort, and it is making things worse.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: If the international community had only supported the Free Syrian Army with the right weaponry in the early stages, Assad could have been ousted and a peaceful transition could have prevailed. Do you share this assessment?</p>
<p>Brahimi: No, because I think they did help the Free Syria Army. But the thing is they thought that the regime was going to fall easily &#8212; complete misconception. Syria has a state, it has an army, and it was assumed that it was going to fall just like Libya did.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Might the Assad regime fall at some point?</p>
<p>Brahimi: So far he is still President and Russia and Iran still support him.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Is there any plan you can think of that might put an end to this conflict?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Iraq tells us that military intervention is a very, very dangerous way of solving problems. UN intervention is something else. If you have a peace-keeping mission that comes as part of an agreed solution, that would be different.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What should such a mission look like?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The UN has, I think, 20,000 or 30,000 soldiers that would be there to help the Syrians implement something they have agreed upon. And then you would need to face the ISIS, Jabhat al Nusra and (other radical groups). But first, the Syrians would have to agree for the UN to come in. It doesn&#8217;t look likely today or tomorrow, but this conflict has got to be resolved. And it will be at some point. The question is: How much killing and destruction are we going to have before that happens? People are telling me that Homs looks like Berlin in 1945.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Could the recent ceasefire in Homs be a model for other places like Aleppo?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The government starved the people there into surrender. The negotiation in Homs took place within the war project of the government, and it led to a victory by the government. But a lot of the things that have taken place during the last phase of negotiations over Homs could be part of a peace process. On previous occasions, many among the people who surrendered were arrested. It is alleged that some have been tortured or even killed.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What role do the countries backing each party play?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The Russians have consistently said it was not up to them to ask President Assad to leave office: &#8220;We do not have that much influence over him, even if we wanted,&#8221; they said. The Iranians said they accept that the crisis needs to be solved through negotiations, that at the end there must be free and fair elections and that this could be organized and observed by the United Nations. But then they said that, of course Assad would be allowed to stand if he wants. All three &#8212; Russia, Iran and Iraq &#8212; are supporting Damascus and delivering a lot of aid to them; probably money and definitely weapons.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: How about the support for the armed opposition?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The Saudis, the Qataris and the Turks are supporting all kinds of political groups and armed groups. The foreign minister of Saudi Arabia said several times that the Syrian people are defending themselves against a brutal regime and it is legitimate to help them protect themselves.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: We have been told that the Saudis even refused to meet with you.</p>
<p>Brahimi: That&#8217;s a fact. I think they didn&#8217;t like what I was saying about a peaceful and negotiated settlement with concessions from both sides. I am only guessing because I did not hear that from them. The irony is that hired pens for the regime are saying that I am Saudi Arabia&#8217;s man!</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Could the Saudis and the Iranians come up with a solution if they were just to sit down together instead of letting their proxies fight about who will dominate the region?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Saudi Arabia is a very important country. King Abdullah is a very wise man and the Iranians, I think, with the new government that they have, also want to be constructive and responsible. Both countries have a responsibility. The region has to start discussing not how to help warring parties, but how to help the Syrian people, their neighbors. The other country that can help is Egypt.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: To what degree does this conflict pose a threat to Israel?</p>
<p>Brahimi: Israel is very happy. Things are going very, very well for them. If Bashar goes it&#8217;s great; if Bashar stays it&#8217;s great. Syria is being weakened. Syria had some kind of strategic weapon with their chemical weapons and that&#8217;s gone. So Israel is doing very well, thank you very much. You don&#8217;t need to worry about them.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: It sounds like you are saying that the Israelis are leaning back and saying: &#8220;Great, our enemies are killing each other.&#8221; Is the world that cynical?</p>
<p>Brahimi: I&#8217;m sure they are saying that. It&#8217;s a realistic point of view. Ask your Israeli friends; they will tell you it&#8217;s so.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What is the true story about the use of chemical weapons in this war?</p>
<p>Brahimi: They have been used, but there are conflicting views about who the culprits were. The UN was specifically requested by the Security Council to merely establish that chemical weapons were used. Not everyone agrees that it was the Syrian government who used these chemical weapons.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: The West considers it fact that the Syrian government was responsible.</p>
<p>Brahimi: As I said, the UN investigating mission was strictly ordered NOT to try to determinate who the guilty party was. Now, from the little I know, it does seem that in Khan al-Assal, in the north, the first time chemical weapons were used, there is a likelihood that it was used by the opposition. Regarding the use of chemical weapons on Aug. 21, 2013 in the suburbs of Damascus, it is a fact that for the West and perhaps most people in the region, the responsibility lies with the regime. Moscow and Tehran say they are equally certain that the government DID NOT use chemical weapons anywhere. It is a great pity the UN was under strict instructions not to try to point the finger at anyone. More recently, there are again allegations that chemical substances have being used. I hope this time the UN will be asked to do its best to find out who the guilty party is.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What was the effect of US President Barack Obama not having done anything after poison gas was deployed in Syria; after the red line had clearly been crossed twice? Is America&#8217;s unwillingness, or inability, to intervene a dangerous portent?</p>
<p>Brahimi: I think that Obama &#8212; and the Russians &#8212; decided that, rather than take punishing action, they would solve the problem at its roots, and they may have done that. From their point of view, and from Israel&#8217;s, that is the better solution. But many Syrians on both sides are rather unhappy that the government is giving up the only strategic weapons they have; a weapon that was acquired at enormous cost to the people of Syria.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What do you think will ultimately become of Syria?</p>
<p>Brahimi: It will be become another Somalia. It will not be divided, as many have predicted. It&#8217;s going to be a failed state, with warlords all over the place.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: What can the international community do, Europe in particular? What should Germany do?</p>
<p>Brahimi: The people in your governments know how dangerous this crisis is and how important it is to support a political solution.</p>
<p>SPIEGEL: Are you referring to the 320 Germans that have thus far joined ISIS?</p>
<p>Brahimi: And to the 500 or 600 French, the 500 or 600 British, and so on and so forth. There are several thousand non-Syrians. My goodness! These are your nationals that are training in Syria and that are part of ISIS, which believes that you have got to build an Islamic state all over the world, starting with Berlin. That&#8217;s a threat to you, isn&#8217;t it? </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/syria-will-become-another-somalia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Israel and Australia, New Best Friends?</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/israel-and-australia-new-best-friends/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/israel-and-australia-new-best-friends/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 14:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=915</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From BBC News- </strong>The Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu thinks he might have found a new best friend down under.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From BBC News- </strong>Australia has a lot of best friends. Sometimes it’s Japan. Sometimes it’s Indonesia. Sometimes it’s China.</p>
<p>Now, though, the Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu thinks he might have found a new best friend down under.</p>
<p>After a quick call to congratulate the new President of Egypt Abdul Fattah al-Sisi on his election victory, which many regard as far from democratic, Netanyahu singled out Australia for high praise at his weekly cabinet meeting in Jerusalem on Sunday.</p>
<p>It came after Australia last week stepped into the always-combustible territory of Middle Eastern linguistics, and seemingly changed its position regarding whether East Jerusalem is “occupied.”</p>
<p>Last week the Australian Attorney General George Brandis issued a statement saying: “The description of East Jerusalem as &#8216;Occupied East Jerusalem’ is a term freighted with pejorative implications which is neither appropriate nor useful.”</p>
<p>The statement was made in consultation with the Australian Foreign Ministry, after Brandis had been challenged in parliament over his failure to refer to East Jerusalem as occupied.</p>
<p>Netanyahu was quick to offer his appreciation of Australia saying the remarks had taken “courage” and calling it “refreshing given the chorus of hypocrisy and ignorance.”</p>
<p>The Israeli Prime Minister’s spokespeople took to the twittersphere to reiterate the thank you message.</p>
<p>Others though were not best pleased.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority reportedly summoned Australia’s representative to explain the change in position.</p>
<p>Palestinian Foreign Minister Riyad Al Maliki called it a “radical change in Australia’s position on Palestine.”</p>
<p>Independent Australian Senator Nick Xenophon said it was “an extraordinary and reckless departure from the bipartisan approach of the last 47 years.”</p>
<p>“Even Israel’s strongest ally, the United States, does not hold this position,” he added.</p>
<p>Jerusalem is at the heart of the Middle East’s most intractable conflict between Israelis and Palestinians.</p>
<p>The Old City in East Jerusalem contains some of the holiest sites of Islam, Judaism and Christianity.</p>
<p>Israel captured East Jerusalem along with Gaza, the West Bank, the Golan Heights and the Sinai Peninsula during the 1967 Six Day Arab Israeli war.</p>
<p>East Jerusalem was annexed by Israel taking full control.</p>
<p>The Sinai was returned to Egypt under a piece deal signed in 1979.</p>
<p>Almost the entire international community, including the United States, does not recognise Israel’s annexation of East Jerusalem</p>
<p>The United Nations and  the International Court of Justice regard East Jerusalem as occupied territory.</p>
<p>President Obama has called for the ending of “the occupation, which began in 1967.” Although in his speech to the United Nations General Assembly he did not specify if he was referring to East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The United States, European Union and the United Nations all believe a future Palestinian state should be based around the pre-1967 borders.</p>
<p>The Palestinians want East Jerusalem to be their future capital.</p>
<p>Israel regards a “United Jerusalem” as its capital although most countries do not accept this and have their embassies based in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Australia has not said whether it will move its embassy from Tel Aviv to Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&#8216;Strong supporter’</p>
<p>So Australia is seemingly going out on a limb.</p>
<p>The country has long been regarded as a strong supporter of Israel.</p>
<p>Along with Israel, Australia was one of only 14 out of 194 UN members to oppose Palestine becoming a member of Unesco, the United Nations education, and scientific and cultural organisation in 2011.</p>
<p>Australia abstained from the vote in 2012 that saw Palestine become a “non-member observer state.” Forty other UN members abstained. 138 voted in favour and 9 voted against.</p>
<p>Australia’s support for Israel is contentious here.</p>
<p>The former Labor Foreign Minister Bob Carr has recently said that extreme right-wing Israeli lobbyists here had an extraordinary influence on Australian policy in the Middle East under former Prime Minister Julia Gillard that he regarded as “very unhealthy.”</p>
<p>Carr’s comments were strongly criticised by the Israeli government and some of the country’s supporters.</p>
<p>Why Australia has chosen now to change its position is not clear.</p>
<p>It’s possible Brandis was speaking off the cuff or out of turn, but the clarifying statement suggests not.</p>
<p>The country has a relatively small Jewish population of about 100,000 (0.4 percent of the total).</p>
<p>The Arab population is much larger: roughly 300,000 people, mostly of Lebanese origin, but including around 7,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Israel’s critics will say the change on policy shows the influence of the lobby group Carr talked about.</p>
<p>The U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said continued expansion of Jewish settlements in East Jerusalem and the West Bank was one of the primary reasons for the collapse of recent peace talks.</p>
<p>Israel has been warned it is currently facing increasing international isolation.</p>
<p>That’s why the Israeli government will value the fact that it still has a friend in Australia. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/11/israel-and-australia-new-best-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Living Like Kings</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/06/living-like-kings/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/06/living-like-kings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 09:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Watch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=909</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>Video Watch-</strong>The Christchurch Earthquake left the majority of its population devastated, but for a small group of homeless people, disaster brought about luxurious living opportunities - a taste of what it’s like to live like a king. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Video Watch-</strong>The Christchurch Earthquake left the majority of its population devastated, but for a small group of homeless people, disaster brought about new and luxurious living opportunities &#8211; a taste of what it’s like to live like a king. </p>
<p>This short is part of a ten-documentary series on New Zealand, Watch the other ones here: vimeo.com/channels/loadingdocs</p>
<figure class="o-container vimeo"><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/96458672" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" title="Living Like Kings" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/06/living-like-kings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Feudal Rapists</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/05/indias-feudal-rapists/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/05/indias-feudal-rapists/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=906</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From the New York Times-</strong>The understanding of the two young girls' deaths in Uttar Pradesh will be incomplete until we recognize the role of the caste system in India’s rape crisis.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From the New York Times-</strong>When a distressed father is reporting his daughter’s disappearance to a policeman in India, there are some questions he doesn’t want to hear. “What is your caste?” is one of them. Yet, the father, Sohan Lal, said this was the first thing the police asked him last Tuesday, when he begged them for help. After revealing his low-caste background as a Shakya, Lal said the officers mocked him and refused to lift a finger.</p>
<p>Hours later, Lal’s daughter, 12, and a female cousin, 14, were found hanging by their scarves from a mango tree in Katra Saadatganj, in the state of Uttar Pradesh. They had been raped. His daughter had last been seen with a group of brothers from the Yadav caste, which is the dominant caste in the village.</p>
<p>Our understanding of their deaths will be incomplete until we recognize the role of the caste system in India’s rape crisis.</p>
<p>For much of India’s history the lower castes, especially the Dalits (once known as untouchables), have been routinely raped by the landowning upper castes. Better legal protections, urbanization and social mobility have helped reduce caste-based discrimination, but not enough. Dalit women are still the most likely to be victims of gang rapes. An analysis of Uttar Pradesh’s crime statistics for 2007 by the People’s Union for Civil Liberties showed that 90 percent of rape victims in 2007 were Dalit women.</p>
<p>Since December 2012, when a 23-year-old woman from the Kurmi caste, another low caste, died after being gang raped and attacked with an iron rod by five men in a moving bus, India has been undergoing a process of soul searching. Yet the caste system has not been mentioned enough in the debate. While attacks against Western tourists and women in urban centers have attracted a great deal of attention, rapes of lower-caste women routinely fail to provoke an outcry. Prime Minister Narendra Modi, for example, has yet to condemn the rape and murder in Katra Saadatganj.</p>
<p>It is no surprise that the caste system, and the unequal society it produces, leads to moral blind spots that hide rapes from public view. Caste historically determined where you lived, what you did, whom you married, even what you ate. In many villages, those rules are still in place, decades after caste discrimination was banned.</p>
<p>Much of the caste-based sexual violence emerges out of a feudal sense of entitlement among some upper-caste men. “You have not really experienced the land until you have experienced the Dalit women” is a popular saying among the landowning Jats, a politically powerful group that, despite being relatively low caste themselves, are above the Dalits.</p>
<p>Though upper-caste men are rarely imprisoned for raping Dalits, they have a widely accepted defense at their disposal, should they ever need one: They would never touch a lower-caste woman for fear of being “polluted.” In one famous  1995 case, a Dalit woman’s allegations of gang rape were dismissed by a judge who claimed that “an upper-caste man could not have defiled himself by raping a lower-caste woman.”</p>
<p>Caste discrimination is exacerbated by corrupt and inefficient governance, which encourages people to seek political power through caste allegiances. Caste bias seems to have been at work in the Katra Saadatganj case. One need only look at the names of the accused brothers (Pappu Yadav, Awadhesh Yadav and Urvesh Yadav) and that of the head of the police station (Ram Vilas Yadav) for evidence that they belonged to the same caste. Two more police constables involved are also Yadavs.</p>
<p>When the police and judiciary cannot be relied on to resolve disputes, rape often becomes a means of retribution. This has been apparent in Hindu-Muslim riots as well as in intercaste conflict. “Rape is a weapon to silence the assertions of the community. A way to teach us a lesson. To show us, including our men, that they are helpless and cannot protect their own women,” said Asha Kowtal, a Dalit activist.</p>
<p>Such thinking seems to have been at work in March, in the state of Haryana, when four lower-caste girls were gang-raped and dumped on a train station platform more than 100 miles from their homes. There is evidence that a conflict between Dalits and Jats precipitated the attack. According to the Indian newspaper Mint, a land dispute led Jats to declare “a social and economic boycott against the Dalits,” perhaps culminating in the gang rape.</p>
<p>We will never be able to address India’s rape crisis if we remain blind to the machinations of caste discrimination. In the past, it has taken gruesome cases of violence to ensure coverage of rape. Indeed, perhaps the only reason the Katra Saadatganj hangings attracted attention was that grisly photographs of the dangling bodies were published in Indian newspapers and circulated on social media, despite complaints by Dalit activists that this was disrespectful.</p>
<p>But we cannot rely on the shock value of particularly horrific cases to lead to change; we need structural solutions. The government should start by amending the 1989 Prevention of Atrocities Act, which is designed to address caste-based violence. The conviction rate under the act is notoriously low &#8211; according to a 2012 report, more than half of all cases are closed before they reach the courts. In the case of Lal’s daughter and her cousin, the police did not register the crime under the act at all. Amendment proposals that would ensure crucial witness protection, more legal support and special courts are sitting in Parliament right now, awaiting approval.</p>
<p>There is no doubt that it was wrong for the police to ask Lal about caste. But for the rest of us, when it comes to understanding India’s rape crisis, not talking about caste is just as bad. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/06/05/indias-feudal-rapists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The French Far Right Aims High</title>
		<link>http://www.iht.com/2014/05/28/the-french-far-right-aims-high/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iht.com/2014/05/28/the-french-far-right-aims-high/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 10:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saskia De Rothschild]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iht.com/?p=899</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<strong>From Spiegel Online-</strong> After its triumph in European elections on Sunday, the French far-right Front National is hoping to increase its power back home, with Marine Le Pen aiming for the presidency in 2017. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>From Spiegel Online-</strong> After its triumph in European elections on Sunday, the French far-right Front National is hoping to increase its power back home, with Marine Le Pen aiming for the presidency in 2017. With François Hollande&#8217;s popularity plummeting, it is not out of the question.</p>
<p>Marine Le Pen shed tears of joy after her triumph in European Parliament elections on Sunday. When she arrived after midnight at a Parisian night club for the victory celebration with her fellow party members, the head of the far-right Front National (FN) embraced fans and family before letting the champagne flow. Marine&#8217;s father Jean-Marie, who was re-elected to the EU body for the seventh time, was also on hand to congratulate his daughter. &#8220;It was a historic victory,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>By Monday morning, the emotional evening had already been forgotten and strategists were once again busy at work at the party&#8217;s headquarters in Nanterre. Until Sunday&#8217;s election, the Front National had occupied but three seats in European Parliament &#8212; one each for Marine, her father and his political companion Bruno Gollnisch &#8212; and had led a largely unnoticed existence on the political fringes in Brussels. Now, though, the party&#8217;s caucus will grow by 21 representatives.</p>
<p>After pulling in a triumphant 25 percent of the vote, the Front National will now have the largest number of seats of any French political party in the European Parliament. Marine Le Pen has every intention of using the party&#8217;s presence at parliament&#8217;s headquarters in Strasbourg and Brussels for political gain. Some within the far-right in France are already considering their political futures &#8212; all the way up to the presidential palace in Paris.</p>
<p><strong>The &#8216;Long March&#8217;</strong></p>
<p>The first step in the &#8220;long march,&#8221; as Marine Le Pen has termed it, is the creation of a party group in the European Parliament comprised of skeptics of the euro common currency, EU opponents and the far-right or right-wing populists. Doing so would provide the parties with greater access to money and key posts and would also raise their profile. To create a group, at least 25 members of parliament from seven different EU member states must join together in a bloc. Given the divergent ideologies on Europe&#8217;s right wing, that won&#8217;t be an easy task.</p>
<p>The only true support Le Pen can count on is from the Austrian right-wing Freedom Party. Right-wing populist parties in Belgium and the Netherlands failed to deliver on Sunday, managing only disappointing results. Meanwhile, radical political forces in Denmark and Britain have said they will not join an alliance with the Front National.</p>
<p>Despite Le Pen&#8217;s triumph &#8212; which the front pages of France&#8217;s newspapers described as a &#8220;Big Bang,&#8221; a &#8220;repudiation&#8221; and even an &#8220;earthquake&#8221; &#8212; right-wing populists will remain a minority among the 751 members of the European Parliament  &#8220;They won&#8217;t have enough influence to determine policy direction,&#8221; FN expert Joel Gombin told French news station BFM. &#8220;On the contrary,&#8221; the sociologist said. &#8220;The relatively good showing of the euro opponents will force existing EU parties to increase their cooperation.&#8221;</p>
<p>That, though, is of little consequence for Le Pen and the Front National. This election cycle clearly demonstrated that the party&#8217;s anti-EU message, and its criticism of an EU that takes power away from member states, is attractive to both workers and young voters.</p>
<p>To be sure, the French far right&#8217;s success is also the product of French voters&#8217; frustration with the country&#8217;s economic malaise and a growing disillusionment with established political parties. Indeed, the Socialists and the conservative UMP are increasingly perceived as being muddled, unreliable or even corrupt. To capitalize, Marine Le Pen has refashioned Front National&#8217;s ideology from the ground up, and now appears to many in France as a modern and dynamic force.</p>
<p>Conquering France One Step at a Time</p>
<p>Thus, Sunday&#8217;s success is seen as but a stage victory among Front National&#8217;s leaders. They have set their sights on more than EU institutions in Brussels; they also want power back home. &#8220;Conquer France first, then destroy Europe,&#8221; Louis Alliot, deputy head of the party as well as Marine Le Pen&#8217;s companion, said of the strategy.</p>
<p>With 4.5 million votes, the party didn&#8217;t fare as well on Sunday as it did during the 2012 presidential election, when it attracted 6.5 million French voters. Still, the party did manage to attract around 11 percent of all eligible voters, which has sparked hopes among FN supporters for the 2017 presidential campaign.</p>
<p>In order to position Marine Le Pen as a realistic alternative to the mainstream parties, the far-right is focusing on conquering the country one step at a time. Next year&#8217;s regional elections could prove decisive. Of the 21 regional administrative bodies where elections are to be held, 20 are currently led by the Socialists.</p>
<p>If the left fares as poorly in those elections as it did on Sunday &#8212; the Socialists managed just 14 percent &#8212; the FN could profit from its continued decline. Marine Le Pen could also stand a real chance in a match-up against President François Hollande. Current polls show that, with a public approval rating of just 11 percent, Hollande is the most unpopular president of France in decades.</p>
<p>But is Le Pen&#8217;s shot at the presidential palace little more than wishful thinking? &#8220;In the past, the Front National has only had bastions of support in certain areas,&#8221; says political scientist Gombin. &#8220;But with this election, FN has become a national party. Next to the traditional left and right, it has now risen to become France&#8217;s third political force.&#8221;</p>
<p>(Translated from the German by Daryl Lindsey) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iht.com/2014/05/28/the-french-far-right-aims-high/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
